<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Secret Lores</name>
		<description>Secret Lores</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
		<file name="secret lores.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bolle-dev/AIME/master/aime/secret%20lores.xml" />		
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Ancient Lore" type="Archetype Feature" source="Willem" id="ID_WILLEM_AIME_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCIENT_LORE">
		<supports>Secret Lores</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your knowledge stretches back to the Elder Days. You know the names of the Two Trees, the Tale of the Three Jewels and the terror of the Great Enemy Morgoth. You’ve heard the tales of the Elven Kingdoms of Beleriand, now lost beneath the sea, and the stolen halls of the Dwarf Lords, and you know of the rise and fall of the Dúnedain. You may make Intelligence (History) ability checks without penalty regarding ancient matters.</p>
			<p>Additionally, if you do not have it already, gain proficiency with History.</p> 
		</description>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
		</rules>	
	</element>
	<element name="Birds and Beasts" type="Archetype Feature" source="Willem" id="ID_WILLEM_AIME_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BIRDS_AND_BEASTS">
		<supports>Secret Lores</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have learned the secret speech of a specific breed of animal, such as the speech of eagles or foxes. You can communicate with them using skills such as Deception, Insight, Intimidation and Persuasion. Animals may be persuaded to carry messages, spy on areas or even lead a Master Scholar to food and water.</p>
			<p>The communication is limited to the knowledge of the animal in question and animals tend to care only about the things of their world, such as food, shelter and predators, paying little attention to the goings-on of larger creatures, however,  a great deal of knowledge can be gleaned from their speech, and while a songbird might not be able to tell an Orc from a Hobbit, she will note which is despoiling the forest.</p>
			<p>You may choose this secret a second time. If you do, your knowledge expands from a specific breed to all creatures of a similar kind and you gain Advantage on your Charisma skills regarding them. For example, when you first select this secret, you learn the hooting speech of owls; with your second, you learn the tongues of all birds and gain their favour</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Birds and Beasts" type="Archetype Feature" source="Willem" id="ID_WILLEM_AIME_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BIRDS_AND_BEASTS_2">
		<supports>Secret Lores</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have learned the secret speech of a specific breed of animal, such as the speech of eagles or foxes. You can communicate with them using skills such as Deception, Insight, Intimidation and Persuasion. Animals may be persuaded to carry messages, spy on areas or even lead a Master Scholar to food and water.</p>
			<p>The communication is limited to the knowledge of the animal in question and animals tend to care only about the things of their world, such as food, shelter and predators, paying little attention to the goings-on of larger creatures, however,  a great deal of knowledge can be gleaned from their speech, and while a songbird might not be able to tell an Orc from a Hobbit, she will note which is despoiling the forest.</p>
			<p>You may choose this secret a second time. If you do, your knowledge expands from a specific breed to all creatures of a similar kind and you gain Advantage on your Charisma skills regarding them. For example, when you first select this secret, you learn the hooting speech of owls; with your second, you learn the tongues of all birds and gain their favour</p>
		</description>
		<requirements>ID_WILLEM_AIME_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BIRDS_AND_BEASTS</requirements>	
	</element>
	<element name="Dark Knowledge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Willem" id="ID_WILLEM_AIME_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_KNOWLEDGE">
		<supports>Secret Lores</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Dark and terrible is the lore of the Enemy and you, perhaps, know more of it than is safe. Upon selecting this secret, you learn the Black Speech of Mordor and can make ability checks about information regarding the Shadow and its followers without penalty. Additionally, if you do not already possess it, gain proficiency with Shadow-lore.</p>
			<p>Finally, when you learn this Secret, you gain 4 Shadow points.</p>
		</description>
		<rules>
		<grant type="proficiency" id="ID_WILLEM_AIME_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SHADOW_LORE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Natural World" type="Archetype Feature" source="Willem" id="ID_WILLEM_AIME_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURAL_WORLD">
		<supports>Secret Lores</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You know the secret properties of many plants, for good and ill, readily identifying natural poisons. You can tell if a beast is natural or not just by looking at it. While you may not have met them, you know of the existence of the Shepherds of the Trees, the Ents of Fangorn Forest. With a successful DC 15 Intelligence (Nature) ability check you can correctly identify a Blighted area, and can guess roughly what caused it to become blighted. If you travel through an area whose blight you successfully deduced, you have advantage on your Wisdom saving throw against Corruption</p>
			<p>In addition, if you do have it already, gain proficiency with the Nature skill.</p>
		</description>
		<rules>
		<grant type="proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Runes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Willem" id="ID_WILLEM_AIME_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNES">
		<supports>Secret Lores</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You know the secrets of reading old runes, from the ancient Tengwar to the Alphabet of Daeron – the Angerthas Moria. You are adept at finding lore hidden within cunning texts and have advantage on Intelligence (Lore) ability checks regarding all such matters.</p>
			<p>Finally, you can automatically discern where Dwarven moon-letters have been inscribed (though you cannot read them without the correct moon!).</p>
		</description>	
	</element>
	<element name="Works of Elder Days" type="Archetype Feature" source="Willem" id="ID_WILLEM_AIME_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WORKS_OF_ELDER_DAYS">
		<supports>Secret Lores</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You know of the wondrous creations of the Elven-smiths of Eregion and the other great smiths and craftsmen of yore, and know some of the ways their works can be employed by those with the right knowledge. You can identify the properties of wondrous artefacts by making a DC 15 Intelligence (Investigation) ability check. On a success, you can identify one Blessing and make a decent guess at other abilities that might be hidden within such an item.</p>
			<p>In addition, gain proficiency in three artisan’s tools of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Secret Lore)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TINKERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SMITHS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_POTTERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_PAINTERS_SUPPLIES|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_NAVIGATORS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_MASONS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_LEATHERWORKERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_JEWELERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_GLASSBLOWERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_FORGERY_KIT|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_COOKS_UTENSILS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_COBBLERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CARTOGRAPHERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CARPENTERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CALLIGRAPHERS_SUPPLIES|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_BREWERS_SUPPLIES|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_MINERS_TOOLS" number="3" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
</elements>	
